I have nine as no recommendation for appointment of Lynn for appointment by him again.
I'm going to the Department of Florida to complete the unit, and I'm inspired by Brent
Brassfield for a term of the expire 829-22 long time, seven year terms on that board.
I talked to four men of Brassfield the other day, and he has served not only as mayor for
long time, but also on the MBI board, and he's just really got a lot of other things going
on, and has to be replaced if possible, and I know that being in talk to Lynn, and I think
she's not standing nominee, and so I'm putting four third name for you, consideration.
Oh, my turn.
Most of the improvement of the recommendation is going to be on for appointment to the MBI.
Okay.
We have a second.
Second.
We'll call please.
Joseph.
What's then?
Aye.
Forster.
I don't think there's ordinance to zero on seven national away, which is basically the
same item that we go with in the SUA meeting, the MSUA meeting, which again just to reiterate,
is putting off any increases in the usage rates on utilities until April of 2018, but the monthly
customer charge will go up 30 days and 80 cents, so we're almost 80 cents, 30 days after
the passage of this ordinance.
There are no questions at entertain a motion.
I'll make a motion there.
And a second.
I'll say hello.
We'll call please.
Weston.
Time for aster.
Aye.
Joseph.
And item number 11 is ordinance two.
Just zero one seven oh nine, which again, just like in the MSUA meeting is a meeting, the
purchase power, adjustment schedule, the PPA, so that at any point, anticipated not until 2018,
although something could happen, but in effect 30 days after, we have, if we approve
this ordinance, if there are any negative PCA adjustments from GRDA, those differences would not
be passed on, but instead would be retaining in a walkbox for capital improvements to our electrical
system.
Do we have a motion to approve item 11?
Make a motion to approve.
And a second.
I'll second.
We'll call please.
First.
Aye.
Weston.
Johnson.
Aye.
All right.
I'm 12.
It's said, did C17102 for a street improvement, which cracks in the market, so it's an
pavement marking, Alicia, or even not?
Well, how are you?
Good.
Mike.
Okay.
We opened the beds last Friday.
Good.
One bed.
And it was from Vans Brothers, and it was for 308.
Vans Brothers.
766138 and the list that we're going to be talking about in the next item was on there.
I feel very comfortable with fans, but there's other ones that did the last micro-surfacing
that we did.
We had estimated this to be about a $700,000 deal and they came in extremely low and I didn't
question them a lot on that, why they came in so low on it, but I made sure that they
did.
They said they were going to do what we asked them to do.
We're thinking maybe the oil prices last time were extremely high last year and we had
three different companies.
So when you added it up and you had your fans' brothers and you had the striping company
and you had the crack and sale company that that possibly gave us a break on that.
Because they're doing all three.
They're taking care of all three because if you'll remember the last time that we did
it, we were kind of held up on our micro-surfacing because we were waiting on the crack
ceiling.
From the other company this, we'll solve that problem because it will be a seamless.
So you're comfortable with the quality of what they've done for worse in the past and you're
comfortable that even though the number came in considerably lower than expected, they
understand what the specs are and it'll meet those specs.
Yes.
We had several conversations and they even attended the pre-bid meeting that we have.
And you fill the reason you didn't have anybody else, there's nobody else wanted to do it.
I mean why do you, you know, the micro-surfacing there about that only people around here
that they're there, they're huge, they're just familiar with what else we're ironed and that's that.
So I think they're the only, that's why we got them now.
The crack ceiling, I can't tell you why we didn't get other people to bid on that.
And you'd think with some competition, they're pricing would have been even lower, but
I think the crack ceiling's a totally different deal.
And so they might not have been able to get somebody, they might, the crack ceiling contractors might not have been able to get
a micro-silling surfacing contractor to go in conjunction with it.
Because you did it, the bill was a package.
It was not.
It's been a bit piece milling it out because we didn't want to run into what we ran into.
The delays for us want to get this one done quickly.
So the challenge is how do we make sure there is aggressive next time?
Yes.
So I mean, it sounds like we've got a good deal this time, and we should be thankful for that.
But we need to, well, seriously, we need to, next time we go off to bed, make sure that everybody stays really competitive.
And, at least you read, it's just explained for anybody that's watching the kind of the route with this crack ceiling and micro-surfacing.
It was low that was due for the roads that we want to...
Right.
So you mean, you meant brief on that just a little bit if you don't mind.
Oh.
Also, in an associate's stead, I wrote assessment for us.
and they labeled categorize the streets as zero's ones,
two, three, fours and five's, and our twos just need to be
crack sealed, they are in the higher the number,
the worse the shape of the road.
This will take care of most of our threes that we have
that will be able to save and we'll be out the money
to rebuild or to have to go in and mill an overlay.
And so what we did was we tried to take streets that
were in areas that when we got the microsurfacing
and the crack sealing done in this area
and we did the crack sealing in house
that would pretty much take care of that area
and we could move on to another area
and that was our whole goal behind the streets
that we have listed on the microsurfacing.
Please keep in mind we are still going to be doing the maintenance
that we can do on the fours and the five
so that the people that live on those streets
are going to be totally forgotten.
Well because I think that was one of my biggest concerns
when going into this, I was kind of close minded to the fact
that you know, and I'm only going to speak for my wardens
what I've heard from the people in my ward
and there's a couple of streets over there
and I think I've expressed it to me
and it's a hard traffic area for that school
and there's a certain path people take
and that road's rough and when I look at your map
it looks like it's a future CIP and that's what's going to hit on it.
So we're not stopping our current construction
and this is in addition to what we were going to do.
And this will make it to what we can leave those alone
and concentrate on those other streets.
It frees up more time to be able to do those
and our next goal is to do what we call the fours and five.
So I'm sure that's probably...
Yeah, it's not really, yeah, it's a manual street over there.
And we've got high traffic, so that'll be one that we're going to work
at first on fours and our fives.
So we recommend Van Sprenerish to do the Microsoft Service
in the fours, fours and fours and fours and fours and fours and fours and fours.
And whatever they start at you guys, we're recording the public
for sure.
We're still going to shut down because...
Yes.
And if we do it in advance, it's always better than the day off.
That was one of the criteria that they communicated with us
with a schedule so that we could notify the public
and kind of keep everybody on a good line of communication.
So it's a good experience.
Anyway, one of the things that's processed last year was how quickly they've moved.
I think we've actually got ahead of us in our notifications.
They were moving so fast.
So I think we'll get that information out quite a bit earlier this time.
Okay.
Winston, when would this start?
Well, they have to get their insurance and everything.
The process is we've accepted you all will accept the ban.
You're going to approve the contract if you so choose
and that is contingent upon them getting their bonds and their insurance
and everything.
We do a notice to proceed.
The contract does say that they have to be done in 120 days.
So from the point in time that they began, it's a 120 day completion day.
And assuming this is approved once that lead time between today and the notice to proceed.
Um, you were from 10 days to two weeks.
Okay. So we fully expect them to be motivated,
started by the rising budget.
And they feel they are very comfortable with it and are extremely happy about getting it done.
Getting it done and are ready to go.
You're scared of me by saying that.
Not sure, quickly.
So do we have a must to approve?
Do you do?
Second.
Well, all plates.
Something.
A quarter.
All right.
So.
I am willing to add as I am 13 street maintenance update.
Let me do a quick introduction because of that.
That's my collection, Sean.
The last time when we had our presentation to about Sean's study,
I better bet I felt a little bad.
I think there was a comment like,
I felt like we had done this study and it looked like very little had been done to my
industries.
And nothing could be further down from the truth.
And I asked them to put together a program and kind of a presentation that
gave you an idea of everything that's been done to date and then what are
plans from here for this summer and for future years.
Granted, when you hit a pot hole, it drives me crazy like everybody else.
But since I've moved back, I noticed some hitting fewer of them.
And a lot of our materials, streets, are actually very good shape right now.
So we wanted to just kind of go over everything including what you've just approved
and then what the next steps are going to be.
So.
I noticed the tireless is 2011.
2012.
So basically this starts with when the contested the bond issue and the
folder, that's the bond issue.
Exactly.
And I'll let them go ahead and make a presentation.
Does that think it's pretty impressive actually?
And I'm going to defer to my call on this because he was part of the
street department when this was going on.
But in front of you, you've got a list.
And just so you know, if you're tied this in red,
it's going to coincide with your red with your red lines.
And so on and stuff.
What you're trying to keep a call on code and so do you.
And then we're staying.
So it's only done as we went back and load.
And the ones you have here in red in 2011, 2012, the street tax.
So that's when we first started the program and many of the streets that will redone.
A lot of them streets that you're going to be on there were reconstructed.
Your first one right here at BJ Tunnel from D Street to J Street.
We did chemically treating a lot of them back then.
So a lot of them were chemically treated and completely rebuilt.
And we have D Street on there from Goodrich.
There's just a lot of streets that we completely rebuilt in the first year.
And a lot of them were high traffic areas that was kind of where they wanted to go with that.
So we went back and tried to find all the information we could on them.
And he's got him right here and we're able to a lot of them that we've read done.
Do you find observation I think I want to make?
Is that I mean we built a lot of streets and we did a tremendous job doing it but we
kind of learned along and why that we didn't have to go as far against on some of us as we did.
And we can stretch our money further. Correct.
So would you re-articulate that battery that you were shown that I just did?
I know Sean touched on in a meeting a month or two ago.
Can you just repeat for the citizens going to fit
when I just tried to describe most of the rebuilt streets?
You can just put it there you go.
Most of the rebuilt streets were kind of one typical section fits all.
We're going to use this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this,
base, we're going to go fix streets and it's everywhere in town.
And moving forward we'd probably like to start looking at here's what we're going to start doing on
our residential streets. And we may be able to thin that up, might be able to use something a little
different in our sub-grates and maybe save a little bit of dollars on some of those.
Now some of your higher traffic streets they may get built the exact same as they are right now.
So I'll say we're going to change everything, but if we can quick do a little bit of studies and
some traffic counts and see if we can thin them sections that'll save you money and we put some of that
somewhere else. Okay. Thank you. Go ahead.
So we did a lot of them and then the CIP 2011 2016 that's just more of the streets that we've done.
Some of it is some crash ceiling and micro-surfacing.
A lot of it is more of that than the reconstruct. There is maybe a few reconstructs on there.
13th there the number one that was a reconstruct. But there's a lot of, there's some of them that are also
cracked ceiling and micro-surfacing and then also the alleys. I think we've done five alleys downtown.
They're in that as well. That's just kind of the timeframe in there when we use that.
So the title for those is 2011 2016 CIP. But what's some of that bond money or was it?
I believe some of it was. I don't know exactly the exact, when the bond money ran out,
right. Maybe it was 2014 when it ran out and I couldn't find exactly when that street was done.
And that's what I thought because I know we didn't scream power up in the two of you.
Yes. Yeah. Some of the purple streets was a combination of the rest of the bond money as well as
whatever funds that had built up in this street. Now they find from when we started setting the money aside.
Yeah, I think most of the alleyways with the time we got to them, the bond money had already went.
And we wasn't coming.
Mark, were you telling everybody what CIP stands for?
Capital and Group and Project.
Okay.
So basically the money that you had five to did for your straight apartment, that was our capital after the project.
When it says future,
we just can't put a date on that.
Well, if we could listen, let's move ahead of time.
Yeah, because we do need to talk about what will happen in the future after ice.
So down here in the green, on the 2017 macro surfacing,
that's street debt.
What?
Okay, we just put the blue up and you haven't talked about the blue.
Okay.
Bullshit.
Now some of your whole money they have bought in that time,
that's last five to 10.
The 2011-16 coordinates, are the ones where I could specifically find that all you did was a slippery steal.
A or a crack seal or a marker cert saying,
I can't do those walking this.
It's not getting any.
Ok, so they came in is a blue.
So on this list of Screams you got.
you've got. Purple candles, both of those purple and blue on the map. So they're both thrown
in the inner and the inner and the inner and the inner. And the risk you have is color-coded with this,
suddenly. And then that leaves us to the green, which is in the 2017 high-cerves, and that's
what's slated for man's brush, we'll hold this up. That you all just approved.
Mike, I can, I'm sorry, go ahead. The green, the 2017 marker servicing is the list that you all
just approved. It might for advanced brothers to come in here in the next month or so and get started off.
So if all goes well by July August, you will, all of these streets on the maps will have been
improved as part of our projects from 2011. So they will have some maintenance from rebuilds done.
In a estimate of the mileage, you've got 116 miles. We have touched half of it since 2011.
When you look up there, it looks like it, but there is a lot of streets that's been touched.
You've also got a lot of resident history still out there. That's a big challenge.
In that future that you ask for, that's where those are. So anything that's still the three more
line that I have already done, they've all had to be built out of the map. And I'll just, in a reason I ask
that is because that's who we hear from the most is the residents. My street didn't get touch and I understand it.
I mean, it's a big elephant with put in bite at a time and so we're trying to do this methodically enough
that with the funds that we have to touch all those streets.
Any other questions?
I had one I actually talked about whatever was going to have to write about something up.
But I would be behind friendship, housing, and progress.
There's very thing we can do there.
I'm surprised getting homes employees and sitting think about that.
That's awful.
I haven't went and patched that thing many times with Limerock.
A contractor went through there and did some work.
That...
It's a mess.
The only thing really that we can do was to keep patching it with Limerock or redo it.
Every single business there has a cut at it.
And when they did it, all the concrete slab has sunk down.
Other than maybe just putting a Limerock in it, it's a bad shape.
Right, exactly.
Because that is something about the future that we're talking about.
We have concrete streets, and we have concrete alleys that have not been touched.
And that's something that we're looking at doing for our future.
One of the things that I've shown I talked about today is we're looking at doing what we would consider an annual bid for our concrete work.
And pricing it at 1,000 square feet, 2,500 square feet on what we would get.
And we would be able to get the contractor in and say, this is what we want you to fix.
And give him a 30 day window to get it fixed.
That alley would be something that would be on that because it is a concrete alley.
And they would go in and fix it.
A lot of it is our concrete panels for our streets.
Those are huge.
We've got a lot of concrete streets that there's just a panel that's messed up.
And this would be a way for us to get our panels fixed.
And get it done in a timely manner and much, much faster than our concrete could get it done.
I mean, you get a whole crew out there say you get a construction company to come in and do it.
They can get it done in 30 days.
And then we can move on.
So that would probably be something that we would be looking at on that.
Well, otherwise that's future, but right now it's horrible.
Well, we're talking future like trying to get it going this summer.
Yes.
Okay.
I mean, I understand that the concrete repairs on concrete streets.
And if one of the things that I asked me is why are we going back with concrete?
And I understand at one time it was cheaper.
Are we going to evaluate streets that we're going to be redeeming?
Well, you know, it is concrete, but it's cheaper to go back.
We're the asphalt and say the money.
I mean, I'm not people who understand that we're not just replacing concrete because that's what it's always been.
We're looking at cost.
Is that correct?
One of the things that we're looking at is on the concrete streets is to not go in and replace the whole street.
We have some streets that in a block section it needs three panels replace and a panels maybe 10 by 12.
Let's just replace them three panels.
That's good to go. And then that's what I understand. But if you go up first treat, yes, there'll be a cost. We'll look at both costs
We'll look with what Shawn's made up. What's going to be the cost difference? How deep do we need to do it?
What's going to be the most? Yeah, but type of most effective way the bank for the buck. Yes
What I'm understanding is is it full of concrete for heavier stuff. I mean, then you're the way that out like you start about out of the way that we're our trash trucks are up and down
So you kind of weigh that out
Yeah, let's concrete even though it's a little might be a little bit more here. The lifespan of it is drastically
Better than if we went with that spot. And that's the pay off for it
So the concrete streets were in the last few longer than that small street and that night
That's that you have to pay for every so often on that asphalt street
You need to look at that in life
Right, what that all costs you would get done. And that's one of those things and I'm assuming that's
That's what you guys are doing and I just want to make sure that that we all
Diving all those eyes and crossing those teeth for that aspect of fine argument or after the bond issue passed
There was this conversation and it's like okay the concrete street lasts 50 years and it may not be exactly right
And asphalt three glass 12 and then you've got to redo it
But originally the concrete projections were so much higher than we saw in a way for them
And then for whatever reason when they started getting the bills that came back in
barely much more comfortable
And so someone saying why we build new concrete streets here for years ago
It made sense then it may not make sense next year
Right, we're talking about but I certainly repairing those makes sense and at the time it made sense when we didn't initially
Maybe it was going to
And I believe at the time there wasn't that much more expensive do concrete
Yeah, that's what I mean
Actually build it out is shocked up how close they were in price
And one of the other things we have to look at when we redo a street too is the drainage
Is it actually a good drainage if we can't get the proper drainage?
We want do we really want to go with the concrete?
It'll hold up with the water compared to asphalt water, so
It just various things
There are a lot of moving parts in trying to make sure that we get like Mike said the biggest thing for our buck
So they're working diligently on that
One of one of the things that I kind of wanted to touch on very quickly is right now
We are very busy with the EP build of ego picture building getting it
Getting it covered up and done once that gets done our plan for this summer is
We are going to start practicing the roads that just need to be crack-cylinder
And we're going to do that in-house
We've got a crack-cylinder machine and we will be doing that and then we're going to start getting the parking lot behind chapters ready to go
And just improving we've got the great alley and we're going to improve yes, sir
Well you've been catching you know, stop talking about you know, you bought the plant and I was going to be there last time and that was the parking lot
You know
when drugs that were they removed the center. Is that going to be, is that what we're looking
out from being at doing that thing in our eyes? I don't know. I don't know. I don't know.
I mean, the future will be moving more well.
And we're not too distant future, actually, because we wanted to get this one done. I feel
remember, as part of Route 66 landing, the parking lot that is, I believe it's between first
street and second. We've got money from Route 66 landing that will be doing something very
similar. There will be adding parking spaces taking out some of the landscaping,
this has gone to see that it's just to make this problem, creating more parking, and then doing
the slurry seal and striping so they're revitalized. And then also the one behind the tag office,
I think, is there our biggest challenge right now? That's a huge challenge. That one is not any of the
fix with just a slurry seal. We're going to have to go in and do some more on it, because it's been patched
and patched and patched. And that's going to take a little more work. We also are going to try to fix
the pop, we call it the pocket park, but it's right there where Route 66 parking is going to be.
I don't remember, it was where Dr. Fuchs had his, his dental business and the other business in there.
We're going to clear that out so that there could be maybe something better put in there or it's just
going to see. Yeah, it's just going to clear it out. It's going to improve the downtown and make it look
better. And then, of course, we've got the incidentals at case-in-point central, the water cut. We want to start
trying to get caught up on water cuts and things like that who are working tandem with our,
our utility side so that we can get the water cuts and the maintenance things like that done.
And then get the concrete bed going and start really getting rolling the concrete streets done. So that's
kind of our plan for the summer and then we're going to, as soon as we, we have a, we call it
the zipper and we've got it to where it's running and we're going to get some practice done on that and then we
want to tackle in front of the Coleman to try to get the drainage. Might explain what the zipper is.
It is a machine that is kind of, it will mill it, but it's not like a big milling machine. We just put it on a
front end loader and it, it, it mills a three foot area. So it's, it's for small jobs. It's what it is
like we can go in and if there's a place we can mill that and overlay that and overlay the whole road.
If there's just the areas, intersections to get them straightened out to where they'll, they'll be smoother.
So it's just a small milling machine for us to be able to use. It's kind of calling in and having to
do a bit for all the big milling jobs. That's so. Sounds like we've got a lot of work. Let's get a job for this.
I've seen it and get it to put raining and get some things, stuff down. And will you, from time to time,
update us, we certainly will. Just be happy too.
Okay, I think of every this is the overarching things since I've been back and I think we're getting a much better handle on it now
But we have a long way to go
Thank you
I don't 14 is continue to discuss discussion and proposed FY 2017
2018 budget we want to make sure we had an agenda item here
There are other questions. I do have one item that I want to bring up
I was thinking Neil I serve on the MDRA authority and that authority has an outstanding loan and the amount of 98,000 and some change
Set right to your 90 or any 6. 96,000 and some change that originated back in
2000 and to read I believe
Anyway, it was when they put in some clockwork and they did some other improvements
You know over the years of being
Several loans at the MDRA took out to continue to do improvements to the facility and this is kind of the last legacy loan
And I think that's out there and
When we were looking at the MDRA budget recently, they budgeted 11,000
I think it's 85 or something like that for payments
We asked the bank to go ahead and work out because they just been paying interest only for a long time on this and paying
Principal when they came and the friends of the coal were helping with the loans
Helping with payments on that to in fact they paid off one of them recently
So this is the last loan that's there. I think this year I figured the other day interest on it or for 12 months three was going to be the
Over 4,000 dollars
And so what I wanted to ask the council if they would consider is taking that money from their
rainy day fund
Not from the M.S. U.A. but from their rainy day fund, some are what we're doing on this building and
And letting MDRA pay that loan off in the RAA would still have an amortization schedule where they would in their budget each year
Pay that rainy day fund back and not saying that MDRA wouldn't be responsible
But we're probably getting maybe a half percent on the money that we have right now on our rainy day funds in various banks
We're paying 4.75% for this loan and I mean it is a separate authority, but it's the city's building
It's a reality of it and
Ultimately if it doesn't get paid the city's land that being responsible not that it wouldn't get paid
But I just feel like we're not being
Prudent with that money to be paying 4.75% when we've got money sitting in the bank at a half percent or once and so I would like for to consider
Paying that off and just letting MDRA pay back the rainy day fund
I think it would take about eight years based on the current amortization
maybe I think it was going to be 10 and a half years with interest to the bank.
Joe, someone that sent me an amortization schedule and lens that I think the total interest
was going to be 26,000 over the life of the law for the public payments.
So we don't have to make a decision on that tonight, but it's the issue that I want to bring
out for everyone to think about and then if the council decides to move forward with that.
Well, Leon, I'll talk with the MDRA about it, which I'm sure they would be happy to not have to
pay the interest.
I think it's a great idea.
I would appreciate it, not necessarily committing you to it, but if it sounds like a good idea,
I'd like to be able to put those numbers in the budget so they're going to be presenting to you
next month.
So I mean, as I said, you can even not approve of it, but it would be good for us to be able to
ascend that you are.
And Joe, I want to declare from the notes that you said, me, this has nothing to do with M.S.U.A. and
transversive M.S.U.A.
So this would just be picking one out of any day you find it and paying it back over a period of time.
Do you think that?
M.S.U.A.
Mayor, can I ask what's the interest rate you consider it?
I have not considered one actually, do you think we need to?
No, but I'll do some research to look at that.
Okay.
If we take the money out of the rainy day, so I'm a little hammer tool we have lived.
I know I've got that information, but I've got about $2 million.
Thank you.
It's just like three after a hour.
We took up the money if we were the way we thought of it.
We required to keep the certain dollar amount in the rainy day.
No, they're...
So by ordinance, you guys have a rainy day fund.
It has three line items, emergency repair and replacement and stabilization.
And every year, you guys actually, in the budget message, the very last page is a certification that says,
we want this much in the rainy day fund.
So every year, you guys decide by approving that certification and you guys sign it.
That says, we want this much.
So if we can have those numbers ready for the June 6 meeting,
if that's when you guys approved the budget, we can actually put that figure that figure into that amount.
And now we withdraw some for the free model.
Yep.
And now we're thinking of withdrawing more for the Coleman.
Well, we do it as it's needed.
So we haven't drawn a dime out yet, because we haven't had any big expenditures.
We've made a provision to draw it.
Yes.
We have it.
We haven't drawn a dime out yet.
And what you may be remembering is, a few years ago, we established a target percentage that we wanted to be in at least some of those funds.
You decide.
discussed it, but it's not in the ordinance.
So it's good to establish a national percentage.
We don't have any tools yet.
20% of I believe are operating expenses.
17 is what I remember.
But our goal was 20.
We were going to get a 17.
Yeah.
And so if we pull this out for example,
the building, we will be putting that percentage down
and that total number down and then paying ourselves back over time.
Or with paying ourselves back plus interest.
No.
If there was a team was asking?
Say again.
Does that what being was asking?
Yeah.
He wasn't asking about the money for the building.
I think he would call his attention because the authority is a separate legal entity.
Should there be an interest rate charge?
And that I get to...
Good question for him to agree with that.
And as far as the 2 million internally,
we could always charge ourselves something,
but we're just taking out of the pocket,
but then we got a right.
Yeah.
Exactly.
And I wonder the thing about the loan.
If you remember when we had the performer to presentation,
it was indicated that if we executed something which we intend to bring you,
some type of a promissory note on the repayment,
it would not affect our rating on the performer.
And if you remember when our performer was very much in the red,
when you factored in the rainy day fund,
we were well in the green.
So we want to make sure that we don't lose that.
That was about the only thing of the performer
that we need to really pay very close attention to,
that was really in the red.
But if you factored in, we're still in very, very good shape,
and naturally.
So there's three items that's in the rainy day fund.
Where does this come out of?
Or does it...
You both are going to go down in three parts?
Yeah, it's got three line items.
And that's because...
So it doesn't...
It doesn't like it fall under one line item.
It just...
It's going to come...
You don't probably come out of the stabilization one.
Okay.
That's what I was wondering.
And those are fun balances.
They're investing various banks around the community.
In other places, it's not all of them.
We'll try to stay under the legal limits.
So...
Do you have a concern?
Well, I guess we need to do some research.
But if you're a research item, give us some feedback.
We can do that.
Okay.
And then we'll...
Maybe gel or de-baby chat to you guys after you get that feedback.
Okay.
Um...
Anything else on the budget?
I've got a couple of things, Mayor.
I actually talked to being...
Before our meeting started, I got a couple of things.
The first one is...
On our claims, and I...
If you've never retake moved a couple of ventures.
Well, I think we've...
We've prepared it tonight.
I didn't have no problem in programming tonight, since it's already May.
But I asked Dean, and if it's okay with you,
on the future, James, the capital ventures,
they're separate at the end of the item.
I might be the only one I'm not gonna...
But for moving forward maybe in the media future. I'm not maybe sometime in the future. I will but I just don't think I'll get it right now
The oven is maids
I'm all for mages. I think Steve will do a great job. I would just ask for me and probably the rest of the council if they want to be more updated
Then we had this last year because we had really had an eddy conversation with Steve
Not about substance
Okay, so he came and spoke to the council
Been a couple of months ago. Do you want to have one meeting?
I think that was one of the things that we talked about last year
But I just to kind of get an idea
You know what we're contributing to them. They'll him to give us some feedback
I know the one we agreed on last year is a mount
That was a big thing for us to want to kind of you know get just
Better understanding of what's been done or how we are with that so and I I kind of agree with Neil on that as well
We will
Take care of that we will have careful solutions
We're going to have to render of mine
The LSA solution is to
Separate you
Want an item on the next agenda to discuss that specific
I know everybody's had a chance to meet with them. That would be up to
First council. I don't care. I mean, I was just doing it to save time
I just didn't want to pull it out of the
Saturday, Jamden
With that if that's what they're going to do I think you want to have an agenda items specifically talking about the services
They provide I mean, I know everybody met with them and I'm not saying we have to without but if you want to, I want to make sure we did
So, I don't
Okay, I do have one thing there was a question that was asked that are last meeting the capital of a loft
Yeah, about capital and
And Tyler's gonna
So I am get in our Kevin's years to we put together what we spent on the truck on the last few years
So 2014 2015 budget
We spent $2800
2015 2016 we spent
$2,145 and
2016 2017 which is the current budget year we spent
$1,395 and ninety seven cents. I want to I don't know what kind of row office in year custom too, but it's a it's a 2005 sterling
And it's I didn't realize this I've always been told this but I call them
a dealership today and actually sterling when out of business in 2008 so the truck
the sterling is no long they don't manufacture heavy-duty and medium-duty trucks anymore so
it's becoming more and more difficult to get parts for this truck I know we have Kevin is
very good about saving money we actually went through the truck and some things we needed to
new to it to update it if we're going to keep running it because if we get a new truck
they will just use this one as our backup so if it ever breaks down we can both use this one
but we came in around 18,000 to 20,000 dollars in repairs for example like the light bar
working on the lift that lifts the hydraulics what else do we look at Kevin that we need to be done
fingers the clutch the clutch is the big thing I mean the clutch could go out I mean it's got very
little clutch left in it hydraulics the carper are those parts just unique to that style of truck
and for the most part yes yeah it's not a universal part well for a roll it's it's universal
to a point for a roll off but it's pretty much just you know so we're starting being out of business
that doesn't mean we still can't get parts and we can still get parts it's just going to be after market
parts let me just let me just clarify what why about this up Kevin not and you always get point you
don't know what will off side do you know where I think what I've been accustomed to but you know what I said
I look at a cap of budgets I'm thinking you know to $200,000 is it where we can get one more year out of
that maybe not and I'm okay with that but I'm thinking $200,000 can we go somewhere else with it yeah
a roll off or unique per se for the unit it's that the roll off is setting on for what you're saying
on a startling yeah parts could become an issue I don't know how long they've been out of business
you start looking at engines transmissions those companies are not out of business and I'm almost starting
to get an engine in I don't know what transmissions in it but those companies are still in business they put
those in starting unless it's a startling known unique transmission engine it might not be and that's that was
the reason I erased my question and this was something that that hit heavy with me last year is
if we're going to do capital improvements on equipment I think it's proven that we we list what kind of
money are we talking about monthly or are you angry or what are you looking at in the future and if it's
$28,000 we got to take that and you know and the only reason I say this is a roll off truck
over that size at $200,000 that doesn't scare me but if you've got multiple issues then yeah there's
a problem with that and that was the only reason that I wanted to kind of know we get feedback from you
so I love those numbers okay fingers I can't I can't protect the fingers you know that's that's that's
that happens and it's what I find more of a problem with roll off his tires
So the fresh mind memory on the cost of the new vehicle, because we budgeted 200,000 is what
we asked for the 2005 Starlink, which we bought it in 2005, it cost 106,000 dollars.
I was gave 200,000 as a budget number when I asked for it in December, January.
Right.
So I would be sure and have no, I would cover being able to purchase the vehicle.
So if we went out to bid for one, it could come in at least.
It could.
We just don't know.
And if you spent the 20,000 dollars, that we, that was, the number mentioned a few minutes
ago, do you think it would, would extend the life of that vehicle three or four years?
I don't know if I would say three or four.
I mean, we could probably get another year or two.
Okay.
But I mean, you never know.
I mean.
And what is the normal life of one of those vehicles?
It sounds like this one's 12 years old.
Yeah.
10, 12 years.
I mean, about 10 years.
And the truck actually has, as of today, when it was parked, it had 212,799 miles on it.
Which like Brian said, 200,000 miles on it, truck is not much.
But this truck ain't been drove on the highway, right?
It's been drove around town.
Here's shit.
That's not highway.
Exactly.
Right.
It has 13,042 hours on it, which is a quite a bit of hours.
Okay.
So, on the high side, it's 200,000 and it has a 10-year life.
It's about 20,000 a year.
If we're going to spend 20,000 this year, I mean, that math says get a new one, I think.
But is there any reason why we can't go off a bed first before we're asked to make that decision?
I mean, we'll go off a bed and we'll present it to you guys tomorrow.
I mean, you also have the ability to protect those.
Do you feel more comfortable with that?
Sure.
I mean, I don't know.
I don't want it to be cleansed, I'm not understanding of what you guys need.
I just, I just want to wake it up.
What does that out?
I mean, because I know hours matter too.
So what is the hour-horses count?
Is that comparable to, or do you guys, look at it that way?
I don't know.
No, ours is a big thing, because a lot of times, you know, there's hard miles, and I don't
know where they're traveling, but yeah, that's just another thing where it sets and it's all
important.
And it's around town, or it's not going to assume any time it's running, pulling and unloading
and unloading robots, your hours are being added.
So, full hours doesn't mean that the wheels are turning all the time, but they're going to
stuff.
Eight-time engines running.
They're working.
Yes.
But a budget is a spending plan.
And when we have a item like this, we plan on spending it on that.
But we can have a number of things that could happen.
We could not have the revenue we've done then.
We said, okay, we push this off.
We go out to beer, find out it's too expensive.
We might go to a plan B. Or I might go to a great deal with things.
this is this is the best thing so anytime we present anything to you as as a you know
we go out to bed and bring it to you you also have the ability to say yes or no
that's what I said and I appreciate that what's going through my mind is I certainly
don't want to spend 20,000 and it ended up being wasted so if we kind of knew the answer
sooner than later absolutely would be helpful so and that's kind of what I've
felt all doing anything that I didn't absolutely have to do to this drug right what
couldn't get money in it you know I'm a place to they'll have specs out tomorrow if
first time so that's how we'll proceed with that okay any other you
had mentioned there's a little discussion about whether we need a work session next
week and obviously basically indicated that a lot of it depends on the calendar talk to
Jill just briefly before we came to order and we're going to just have to have a
resolution adopting the budget by what date is it? the 23rd of June so our intent is right now
we would be presenting the budget for approval on June 6th and if there's any additional work
that needs to be done or anything like that our backup would be our next council meeting on the
20th we can always schedule special meetings if you'd like so there's at this point there's still
ample time to work on the budget we have to have a public hearing no one for doing it yes the
public hearing is planned for the sixth okay and they have to be the same meaning that you approve it
but that's how much I don't want to make sure if you start back in the calendar up you all if we
ended up there's a public hearing budget have to be the budget's passed or you just have to have a public hearing
just have a couple of hearing so if there are some more things yes we're going to run to a
calendar much no if that to anything if we hold the public hearing on the sixth and we hear some things
of extra decisions then you've got until really the 23rd of make those adjustments so if everybody's
comfortable with that we will skip our work session of the Gregory Agil for next Tuesday we'll be
able to plan okay but don't put out a cancellation yeah that's come on and but we're going to anticipate
not having the great Royce schedule meeting okay anything else on budget or new issues I want to say
I went to the open house of the new Travel Center because Friday there was a million people there
it is amazing if you haven't had the opportunity to go out and look have beautiful gifts in the
gift shop and it's just really nice and you don't have to get on the turn pie cut a jump on the camera
you don't have to get on the turn pie but don't change as you need to put them a wife on the reward program
some kind
I didn't have someone ask me why the bathrooms were locked at night and I didn't have any answer for that.
Safety.
But that's what I thought you wanted to be.
I want to be sure that we have attendance there.
There are some more stories in other parts of the state.
Not in my ammo about things that can happen in those and that's what we want to.
Yes.
Well, that's what I thought it probably was.
Unfortunately, we're in that day and age.
How have you 17?
So the manager for me to finish?
I only had one, and I'm going to ask Christie to come out because she said the attack
saying kind of reminded everybody about this.
But this is her project because she's been working on.
So she's she needs to be the one telling you about this.
Well, it was my fault.
I actually forgot to ask the him before the meeting to follow up on it.
This year, we after we did the spring cleanup.
We got together and talked about what?
What did we, you know, what can we do from here?
And one of the things that came up is a used tire round-ups.
So basically what we're doing is may 20 second through June 3rd will be opportunity for citizens
that are both residential and commercial customers of the MSUA to take their tires out
to the solid waste facility, dispose of them and dumpster that Kevin and the guys will have out there
and utilize the state will come out and pick them up.
So we're hopeful that we'll get several citizens and commercial customers to take advantage of that
and help us out, especially right before the mosquito season with all the water that we've had
and use tires are a big attraction for mosquitoes.
You can take an off-road equipment or a stick.
Why are you talking about that?
But I think your tire is off the rim.
It was probably a question of Kevin.
You do have to have proof that you're a customer right when you come out there.
Just like what you have to do on a Saturday on the first Saturday of the month that's a free day.
You've got to bring a bill out to show them that you're a customer.
But for a utility bill and thermal ideas, we'll require on Saturday.
That's what we're going to do for the free tire.
Okay.
And we're going to get the word out to people that's going to be happening.
Well, this was one of the ways that I forgot to mention about before.
We'll put it on after tonight tomorrow.
We'll go up on Facebook and on the city website.
We'll email this flyer out city wide.
So the paper will be helping us there.
The paper and the chains are sitting in the utility bill.
Yeah, that has to be done.
Yeah.
And what's the way it again?
May 20 second through June 3rd.
So it's two weeks.
Two weeks.
And it does capture on June 3rd is the free first Saturday.
So you can take a whole lot of stuff out there.
There you go.
Okay.
Thanks for going.
And one final thing I'd like to wrap up on this is I wanted to thank all of our crews.
Public Works, utilities, police and fire during the last couple of weeks with the high water that we've had.
And unfortunately storms are moving through this week again.
Friday it looks like we can potentially have heavy rain and I did know the ground likes still up around 750.
So we'll be keeping a close eye on it and Glendee even gradually said hi to her did a good job during the year C.
So I'm happy about that.
And just wanted to thank everybody because a lot of hard work went in to keep everybody safe.
And again turn around, don't drown.
We cannot believe the number of people that go around barricades and have to be rescued at high water.
So that's it.
Okay.
I have 16 years of German.
Do I have a most to a German?
Push.
Yeah.
Second.